17630 Lomond Blvd, Shaker Heights, OH, 44120 216-970-1203

Thomps9012@gmail.com

https://github.com/thomps9012

https://www.linkedin.com/in/samuel-joseph-thompson/

https://sjtportfolio.herokuapp.com/

Samuel Thompson

As a Data Coordinator turned Lead Evaluator, I enjoy solving unique problems with critical thought as they arise. I have experience creating full stack web applications that have undergone the Continuous Integration / Deployment process within the DevOps pipeline. A former classroom educator (and current Instructional Specialist), who has strong management skills, a growth mindset, and feels comfortable working within a diverse team environment.

Languages & Libraries: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, jQuery, Bootstrap, React.js, Google Fonts, GitHub, Express.js, Next.js, C#, .NET, MongoDB, Next.js, Material UI, Prisma, TypeScript, Python

Programming Frameworks: Server-Side Data, Server-Data Connections, State and Prop Components, Object Oriented Programming, Responsive Web Design, Microsoft Azure, Versioning Control, Continuous Deployment / Integration, 3rd Party APIs, Stored Procedures, Automation, Modularization

Client EBT Records Weekly Hour Function Counselor Logs https://github.com/thomps9012/weekl https://thawing-shorehttps://counselorlogs.azurewebsites.net 78114.herokuapp.com/ **yHrFunc** http://counselorlogs.azurewebsites.net/Re https://github.com/thomps9012/clientE ports/Home **BTRecords** HTML, CSS, SQL, Node.js, .NET, C#, SQL, HTML, Inline Python, SQL, MongoDB Next.js, TypeScript, Material Styling, GitHub, Microsoft Azure UI, Heroku

An online web application built using TypeScript and a Next.js framework with a SQL / Prisma backend. The application is hosted and deployed on the Heroku platform. Users can create new client records and then interact with the data via a Material UI DataGrid component.

A backend python function that takes data from a SQL structure and transforms it into JSON so the information can be stored in a NoSQL framework (specifically MongoDB). Administrators can then view the organized data in a clear, concise format.

An application that allows counselor and peer supporters to track their interactions with clients. The data is then stored in a SQL database that contains stored procedures which organize and filter data according to supervisor. Hosted on the Azure .NET platform the app has gone through several iterations.

Work Experience

Data Coordinator / Lead Evaluator

Full Stack Web Development Instructional Specialist

Elementary Science Learning Facilitator

Northern Ohio Recovery Association 2021 - Current

Columbia University
University of Connecticut

Tecnologico de Monterrey

Trilogy Education Services 2021 - Present Clark County School District 2016 - 2019

Responsible for the design, creation, and maintenance of cloud-based solutions for client and counselor data. Created several full stack web applications within the object-oriented programming paradigm based on user / business needs. Implemented DevOps practices with CI/CD for data collection and reporting tools that have undergone several versions due to user requests and feedback. Worked with C – level executives and fellow employees on projects listed above.

Taught in an online remote learning environment via multiple cohorts, most notably the Columbia University & Connecticut. Worked with students on topics of HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js, Express, Node, SQL, and NoSQL. The cohorts have been remote since COVID, which has given me experience working with teams in a remote environment, using tools such as Zoom and Slack.

Introduced a technology-based gradebook and parent-teacher portal to fellow educators and families.

Managed and facilitated learning in a blended classroom (1:1 setting) at a diverse magnet school. Taught following evidence-based standards in a personalized learning environment where learners were offered flexibility and choice in creating their learning path.

Education

Full Stack Web Development Coding Boot Camp Graduate

Case Western Reserve University
 2020

Bachelor of Arts in Environmental Studies

- The University of Montana 2015-2016

Graduate from the National Outdoor Leadership School (NOLS)

- NOLS Southwest

2011

Awards

Leadership, Achievement, and Service Scholarship

Received due to graduation with honors from the National Outdoor Leadership School in Tucson

Kain-McKay Scholarship

Earned for a year and half of service with the Montana Public Interest Research Group that culminated in a semester of lobbying for clean, renewable energy at the Montana State Legislature

Extra-Curricular

Student Senator

Represented fellow students in the Associated Students of The University of Montana (ASUM) with a focus on sustainability and transportation issues

Kless Revolving Energy Loan Fund

Managed and distributed funds for clean energy initiatives on campus.